<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Insights</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Data Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio and Shiny Servers with AWS - Part 1</title>
      <link>/post/rstudio-shiny-aws-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rstudio-shiny-aws-1/</guid>
      <description>After realizing how fast I can burn through my free 25 hours on shinyapps.io, I decided to repurpose my RStudio Server to also work with Shiny Server. Here’s my new setup:
 1 AWS EC2 server with an elastic IP address 1 Route 55 Amazon domain linked to the EC2 elastic IP (davisvaughan.com) RStudio Server Shiny Server  In case I ever have to go through this madness again, or if anyone else wants to, I’ve compiled some step by step notes on the setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/about/</guid>
      <description>Who am I? Hi! I’m Davis Vaughan. A Master’s student studying Mathematical Finance at the University of North Carolina at Charlotte. I enjoy all things R, and love automating tasks with it. I’m also a coffee enthusiast, as most R users seem to be.
 What else? I’m the other half of Business Science. We develop open source software for financial analysis. Check out the site to learn more, and feel free to contact us if you’re interested in our consultant services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon RDS &#43; R</title>
      <link>/post/rds-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rds-and-r/</guid>
      <description>Intro Welcome to my first post! To start things off at Data Insights, I’m going to show you how to connect to an AWS RDS instance from R.
For those of you who don’t know, RDS is an easy way to create a database in the cloud. In this post, I won’t be showing you how to setup an RDS instance, but I will show you how to connect to it if you have one running.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>